# Tanvi Sachdeva

Front End/Full Stack Lead

### Contact

**Address** 

Pune, India, 411057

**Phone** 

916 858 8710

E-mail

sachdevatanvi2311@gmail.c

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sachdevatanvi2311/

#### **Certifications**

2021-05

AZ-900 Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals

2021-06

AZ-104 Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator

#### **Skills**

**Javascript** 

Angular

.NET Full Stack

Front end

Backend

Full Stack

8+ years of experience in leading and managing project delivery with significant experience as an individual contributor.

Tech stack - React, Angular, .NET, C#, HTML, CSS, Agile and Cloud, Azure certified, OOPS. More than willing to upskill in newer technologies should the project require. Have experience of working on client side in France.

#### **Work History**

#### 2022-04 -Current

# Application Development Associate Manager

Accenture - International healthcare client

- React 18, Google cloud, Redux, SASS, SCSS,
  Balsamiq, Typescript, React bootstrap, ReactJS,
  Swagger, GIT, Adobe XD, Scrum, TDD, Axios, Http,
  Agile
- Confident in working independently or in a team in a deadline driven environment with quality deliverables.
- Strong communication and organizational skills with an ability to thrive in a fast-paced production deadline-driven environment both internal and client facing.
- Ability to solve complex development problems and produce the highest quality code while striving to push the technical boundaries of online applications
- Ability to work quickly while maintaining strong attention to detail and accuracy while adhering to W3C and accessibility guidelines.
- Strong attention to detail and understanding of UI concepts to provide perspective on front and backend technologies and their overall impact on the creative process.

#### 2019-06 -2022-04

### **Technical Lead**

Sopra Steria India - European aerospace client

- Client European multinational aerospace leader ( Have international experience of working in France on client side)
- Angular, React, Javascript, Typescript, .NET REST Webapi, Agile, GIT, IIS, Mongodb

Scrum

Agile

C#

Leadership and Management

Azure

Project Management

- HTML
- CSS
- Mongodb

Cloud

**Typescript** 

React

- Lead and performed end to end delivery of web applications starting from requirement understanding to implementation to deployment.
   Contribute to the end-to-end codebase of an application including rich frontend, thoughtful web APIs, and well-designed databases.
- Create responsive web applications using Angular.
- Participate in all scrum ceremonies. Involved in scoping and estimation of user stories during PI planning, with Product owners/client/business.
- Mentored Web Application development team members who are on a technical career path and are interested in becoming future technical leads and engineers.

2018-06 -2019-06

#### **Lead Engineer**

HCL Technologies Ltd. - International software client

- Client American multinational technology leader
- ASP.net MVC, GIT, Azure, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript, CSS
- Investigating bugs in software application based on technical expertise and developing solutions in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Mentored team members on technical front so that quality code is delivered with minimal postproduction bugs/issues.
- Effectively manage scope and client expectations on individual assignments.
- Work with an Agile team to deliver applications iteratively, and incorporate feedback into future iterations.

2015-08 -2018-04

## **Product Integration Engineer**

EdgeVerve Systems Ltd. - International telecom client

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- .NET MVC, SQL, Jauery, Javascript, Angular
- Analyze business problems, develop technology solutions to those problems and manage project through its lifecycle.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Providing timely deliverables to client, solving post

production bugs/issues were handled.

2014-09 -2015-07

### **Systems Engineer**

Infosys Ltd. - International telecom client

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- Full stack developer
- C#, .NET, Angular JS, SQL

#### **Education**

2010-08 -2014-07

# Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science And Engineering

Rajasthan Technical University 80%

#### **Honors and Awards**

- Sopra Steria India Limited, Pinnacle Award, Feb 2021
- Sopra Steria India Limited, Pinnacle Award, June 2020
- HCL Live Wire Award, July 2018